

## **MATIAS GIMENEZ** Frontend Developer

## matias.gimenez@gmail.com (+54) - 15 3 282-9461

### **Profile**

I'm a front-end oriented Web Designer and Da Vinci School graduate (2010) who has worked for various high traffic websites, most notably MercadoLibre and DeAutos, where I gained significant first-hand experience in UI/UX development, with equal emphasis on performance and code semantics.

Since 2010, I have worked as a freelancer, developping sites and applications web meeting tight, high-pressure deadlines while ensuring consistent operation.

I am also employed of Eulas in where I'm integral part of 10-person team, which develops E-Commerce web apps for multiple brands.

My passion for technology extends far beyond the day-to-day demands of my work: I keep a constant eye on emerging trends in the field, so that I'm always updated on the latest advances, with the goal of ensuring that the quality and scope of my work are always expanding.

### Skills

Semantic HTML 5	UX / UI Development	PHP / Code Igniter
CSS 3 / COMPASS	DOM / AJAX / JSON	My Sql
Vanilla Javascript	Grunt	Photoshop
jQuery / jQuery UI	WPO	Illustrator
Responsive Web Design	APIs	Fireworks
Progressive Enhancement	GIT	Scrum

### Experience

#### Eulas

05/2015-Actual

- Frontend Developer UI/UX
- Semantic HTML5 • CSS3 / COMPASS
- Vanilla JavaScript / jQuery
- Handlebars
- Frontend Improvements
- Google Apis
- Grunt
- Responsive Web Design
- JBoss
- GIT

#### **DeAutos**

01/2015-05/2015

Frontend Developer UI/UX

- Semantic HTML5
- CSS3
- Vanilla JavaScript / jQuery
- JS Frameworks
- Frontend Improvements
- WPO (Web Performance Optimization)
- Grunt / Gulp
- Responsive Web Design
- GIT

### Mercadolibre

08/2012-01/2015

### Frontend Developer UI/UX

- Semantic HTML5
- CSS3
- Vanilla JavaScript / jQuery Chico UI (JS Framework)
- Components & Libraries Development
- Progressive Enhancement
- Responsive Web Design
- GIT • Grails / Groovy
- Frontend Meetups

# 8a Marketing Comunicacion y Diseño

06/2011-08/2012

## Web Implementer

- Semantic HTML
- CSS
- jQuery / jQuery UI
- PHP, CodeIgniter, My Sql
- Newsletters

# Joptiwebs

2010-Current

- Freelance Development • Corporative Sites, Institutional, Drupal Development.
  - Semantic HTML
  - CSS / CSS3 / SASS
- JS / jQuery / jQuery UI • PHP, CodeIgniter, My Sql

## Education

## Escuela Multimedial Da Vinci

03/2008-08/2010

- Designer & Manager Web sites oriented programming • Photoshop, Illustrator, Flash.
- HTML XHTML / CSS 2.1
- Javascript / Jquery • PHP5 - MVC / Doctrine Framework / Zend Framework
- MySQL
- WAMP

# Universidad Tecnologica Nacional

03/2004-08/2005

1997-2002

## **Technician in Programming**

- Approved subjects: 11/20. • Structure of computer systems, Features OS
- Computer Security (Antivirus, Firewall, Spy, Spam, etc.)
- Maintain an optimal PC.
- Structure of a PC, Micropocesadores, Memories, Peripherals. • C & C++

## Technical School Reconquista de BsAs. (High School)

Computer technician

- C & C++ Visual Basic
- Fox Pro

Matias Gimenez —matias.gimenez@gmail.com —(+54) - 15 3 282 9461